intechopen.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy | IntechOpen

This privacy policy applies to [www.intechopen.com](https://www.intechopen.com/) owned and operated by IntechOpen (hereafter referred to as “IntechOpen”, "We", "Us", or “Our”). This Policy sets out how IntechOpen uses and protects any information that you, the ("user") give when you use this website. IntechOpen is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected at all times. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, you can be assured that such information will only be used in strictest accordance with this Privacy Policy.

IntechOpen does not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personal information to third parties unless they are publicly available as part of the publishing activities, or we have your permission, or are required by law to do so. IntechOpen may change this Policy from time to time by updating this page. You are invited to check this page to ensure that you agree with the changes.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)

1\. WHO ARE WE?

We are IntechOpen, the world's leading publisher of Open Access books. INTECHOPEN LIMITED is a privately owned company registered in England and Wales, No. 11086078 Registered Office: 7th floor, 10 Lower Thames Street, London, EC3R 6AF, UK.

2\. USAGE OF INFORMATION

Registration on the IntechOpen web page is for Authors, prospective Editors and other users who wish to send suggestions. Involvement is entirely optional and voluntary. We use the information you provide to:

  * Allow Authors to access the information they need in order to publish their work
  * Allow IntechOpen to send service email notifications or promotional messages about new publications released
  * Administer your account and customize the service we provide to you and other users
  * Provide your personal details to third parties, as outlined above, offering combined services with IntechOpen, enabling you to share your information and communicate with other users

3\. WHAT WE COLLECT

For the purposes stated above we may collect the following information:

  * First name, Last name, academic/job title, organization/institution and previous publications
  * Contact information in the form of an email address, postal address and country of residence
  * Other information regarding your scientific field of interest, education and work experience
  * Password

4\. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED

In order to deliver a better service, IntechOpen tracks patterns of use on this site. We note which links are clicked on to determine what areas, chapters, and books are of interest to our visitors. As with all websites, we automatically receive from Internet usage, information such as your IP address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data, your mobile provider and your mobile device. We store all data in log files. We use cookies and other technologies to recognize you, study traffic patterns on our website, and customize your experience.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

5\. YOUR RIGHTS

Authors, Co-authors, Editors and Co-editors can choose what information to make available to other users.

With the exception of your e-mail address (which works as a login), you are free to change your personal information at any time. IntechOpen will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personal information changes, you may correct, update, or delete it by making changes through your User Panel, or by contacting us by post at the address given in the contact information listed below.

You can submit a request to close your IntechOpen account at any time. If you no longer desire our services, you can deactivate your account by emailing us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com) or by contacting us by postal mail using the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

6\. OPEN ACCESS

IntechOpen is an Open Access publisher. All published Work will be permanently and freely available on our webpage. Certain personal information such as first name, last name, affiliation and email address shall be publicly visible and available along with the published Work. It is the basis of Open Access to freely share all scientific Work and information associated with those Works.

7\. THIRD PARTIES

IntechOpen will only share personal information with third parties in the specific ways that are described in this Privacy Policy.

In certain situations, IntechOpen may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

IntechOpen does not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law so as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process. Please note that in order to deliver certain services (for example, Chapter publication), we may share information with third parties. To process payments made by you, we share some of your information with the payment processing company we use. While you are entitled to decline to provide the information requested, this may prevent us from providing the services requested. In the case of delivery of hard copies of books to Authors, or other parties ordering such publications, we share with third parties conducting postal delivery services the information required in order to carry out the delivery. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

If IntechOpen is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

8\. E-MAIL POLICY

IntechOpen may send you service communications by email. If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for email/newsletter services, IntechOpen may send information which you might find of interest. You may change your mind and unsubscribe at any time by emailing us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com). Additionally, you can unsubscribe by clicking the Unsubscribe button in all our marketing emails.

9\. SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that it is treated securely. Any sensitive information is encrypted and protected.

Once we receive your information, we will take all necessary precautions to ensure its security in our systems. You will need to use a password to access certain parts of our website and it is your sole responsibility to keep your password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

10\. TRANSFERRING YOUR INFORMATION OUTSIDE OF EUROPE

As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union (“EU”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. By submitting your personal data, you are agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing of information. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

11\. CUSTOMER TESTIMONIALS / COMMENTS / REVIEWS

In the Author Acknowledgments section of our website we post Customer testimonials/comments/reviews. These may contain personal information. Testimonials are stored in a database held within IntechOpen. Prior to posting a testimonial, we obtain the Customer's consent to posting his or her name along with the testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, please contact us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com).

12\. COOKIES & OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

Technologies such as cookies, or similar technologies, are used by IntechOpen and our business partners, affiliates, analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and in gathering demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies from these companies on an individual, as well as an aggregated basis.

We use cookies for user authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

Cookies we use and what they are for

The cookies we use on [www.intechopen.com](https://www.intechopen.com/) can be categorized as follows:

 _Necessary cookies_

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to experience the website fully and use the full range of features and functionalities available to you. These cookies are first-party cookies and can be either permanent or temporary. Without these cookies, www.intechopen.com will not work properly or will not be able to provide certain features.

 _Performance cookies_

These cookies collect anonymous information about how visitors use a website, for example, which pages visitors visit most often, in order to provide a better user experience. These cookies do not personally identify individual visitors. We use these cookies to provide statistics on how our website is used. These third-party cookies could be permanent or temporary cookies.

If you have any questions about the use of cookies on our website please e-mail us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com). We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use cookies, or similar technologies, in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

13\. SECURITY

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com).

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. However, given that the Internet is not a secure medium, there is no guarantee that information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by a breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information and for controlling access to your email communications at all times.

14\. LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide, and such sites are NOT governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy policy applicable to the website in question.

15\. SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as Facebook and Twitter buttons, and Widgets or interactive mini-programmes that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

16\. PERSONAL INFORMATION AND AUTHORS

The summary of Authors' personal information (First name, Last name, academic/job title, Organization/Institution and previous publications) are made publicly accessible on IntechOpen's website. IntechOpen will not send authors unsolicited e-mail messages unless it directly concerns the publishing process, their published work, and other publishing options.

17\. DATA RETENTION

We will retain your information as long as your published work is freely available from our web page, or as needed to provide you services you have requested from us. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services please contact us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

18\. CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will notify you on this page, by email, or by means of a notice on our Home page, 30 calendar days prior to implementing the change.

19\. CONTACT US

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [info@intechopen.com](mailto:info@intechopen.com) or write to us at IntechOpen, 25th Floor, 32 London Bridge St, London SE1 9SG, United Kingdom.

 _This policy is effective from 2019-08-28._
